<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post-rsses on aiPav</title>
    <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post-rsses on aiPav</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://aipavilion.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5: Papers and Purpose</title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/week4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/week4/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;talk-this-friday&#34;&gt;Talk this Friday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.johnchavens.com/&#34;&gt;John C. Havens&lt;/a&gt; will be speaking on Friday (Oct 5), 10-11:30am on &lt;em&gt;Humanities, Cultures and Ethics in the Era of AI&lt;/em&gt;, Wilson Hall 301. He is executive director of the IEEE project on &lt;a href=&#34;https://ethicsinaction.ieee.org/&#34;&gt;Ethics of Autonomous and Intelligent Systems&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=1_JEklX4-NJ1lw4fm6WpJ9rwQK9kw5gPzYwOIfcGXF-A&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; to RSVP (there is also a lunch following the talk).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;interesting-law&#34;&gt;Interesting Law&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;California passed a law about bots impersonating humans: &lt;a href=&#34;http://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billTextClient.xhtml?bill_id=201720180SB1001&#34;&gt;Senate Bill No. 1001: Bots: disclosure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(a) It shall be unlawful for any person to use a bot to communicate or interact with another person in California online, with the intent to mislead the other person about its artificial identity for the purpose of knowingly deceiving the person about the content of the communication in order to incentivize a purchase or sale of goods or services in a commercial transaction or to influence a vote in an election. A person using a bot shall not be liable under this section if the person discloses that it is a bot.&lt;br /&gt;
(b) The disclosure required by this section shall be clear, conspicuous, and reasonably designed to inform persons with whom the bot communicates or interacts that it is a bot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is interesting that it seems to be unlawful for a bot to
intentionally confuse a human, but not for a bot to intentionally
confuse another machine (which is a much more common problem in
actuality today).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reading-assignment&#34;&gt;Reading Assignment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of fall break, there is no meeting next week. The assignment
for Oct 15 will be posted soon (I&amp;rsquo;ll send out email when it is).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4: Hoverboards</title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/week4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/week4/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;paper-ideas&#34;&gt;Paper Ideas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea for your first paper is due &lt;strong&gt;Sunday, 30 September&lt;/strong&gt;. From
the syllabus, the first paper can &amp;ldquo;focus on one aspect of how
artificial intelligence has already impacted society, describing the
impact of technological advances on a social, political, economic, or
psychological aspect of human existence.&amp;rdquo; It is not required that your
paper idea is on this topic though &amp;mdash; anything that is relevant
to the seminar theme (broadly interpreted), interesting, and with a
scope suitable for a 4-5 week effort is reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should post your paper idea on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/aipavilion/&#34;&gt;class
subreddit&lt;/a&gt;. Submit a new text
post (or a link post that links to a PDF) that has a title &lt;code&gt;Paper: your title&lt;/code&gt; and contains:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One sentence: what is your paper about&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1-2 paragraphs that motivate your topic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A short list of things you plan to do (e.g., readings) to develop your idea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best ideas for will make an argument for a non-obvious and
controversial claim and include data to support that argument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elevator Pitches.&lt;/strong&gt; In class next week, you’ll give an elevator
pitch for your idea to the class for feedback. This should be about 90
seconds long &amp;mdash; enough to give a clear idea of your idea and why
it is worth doing, but getting to the point concisely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;assignment&#34;&gt;Assignment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the next class (Monday, 1 October), you should read:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yuval Noah Harari, &lt;em&gt;Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind&lt;/em&gt;, Chapters
18, 19 and Afterword.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aipavilion.github.io/docs/hallpike-review.pdf&#34;&gt;Hallpike&amp;rsquo;s review of Sapiens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tim Urban (&amp;ldquo;Wait but why&amp;rdquo;), &lt;a
href=&#34;https://waitbutwhy.com/2015/01/artificial-intelligence-revolution-2.html&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The
AI Revolution: The Road to Superintelligence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Part
2). (Posted in 2015)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sapiens Response.&lt;/strong&gt; Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve finished &lt;em&gt;Sapiens&lt;/em&gt;, post a
  comment that mentions the most surprising or interesting thing you
  learned from reading it and explains why. &lt;a href=&#34;https://redd.it/9iuzz2&#34;&gt;[Discussion Link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hallpike Response.&lt;/strong&gt; Select one of Hallpike&amp;rsquo;s criticisms of
  &lt;em&gt;Sapiens&lt;/em&gt; (this could be a specific quote from his review, or a
  paraphrase of a main point), and make a case opposing
  it. Alternatively, if you find all of Hallpike&amp;rsquo;s criticisms valid
  and convincing, respond to one of the cases posted with a
  counter-argument. &lt;a href=&#34;https://redd.it/9iv2b5&#34;&gt;[Discussion Link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(There&amp;rsquo;s no response question for the Superintelligence reading, but
feel free to post any thoughts you want on this. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if we&amp;rsquo;ll
get to discussing this next meeting, but it, and readings from
Bostrom&amp;rsquo;s book, will be the main focus of the next few weeks.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3: Money and Thinking</title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/week3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/week3/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div class=&#34;printing&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aipavilion.github.io/docs/week3.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF for Printing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://waitbutwhy.com/2015/01/artificial-intelligence-revolution-1.html&#34;&gt;Loebner Prize (Turing Test)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pandorabots.com/mitsuku/&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s chat with Mitsuku!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The transcripts you read were from &lt;a href=&#34;https://aipavilion.github.io/docs/turingtestexperiments.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can machines think? A report on Turing test experiments at the Royal Society&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Kevin Warwick and Huma Shah, Journal of Experimental &amp;amp; Theoretical Artificial Intelligence, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;upcoming-first-paper&#34;&gt;Upcoming: First Paper&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea for your first paper is due Sunday, 30 September. From the
syllabus, the first paper can &amp;ldquo;focus on one aspect of how artificial
intelligence has already impacted society, describing the impact of
technological advances on a social, political, economic, or
psychological aspect of human existence.&amp;rdquo; It is not required that your
paper idea is on this topic though &amp;mdash; anything that is relevant
to the seminar theme (broadly interpreted), interesting, and with a
scope suitable for a 4-5 week effort is reasonable. We&amp;rsquo;ll talk more
about this next week, but you should start thinking of ideas for your
paper now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;assignment&#34;&gt;Assignment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the next class (Monday, 24 September), you should read:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yuval Noah Harari, &lt;em&gt;Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind&lt;/em&gt;, Chapter
14-17 (if you want to read further, we&amp;rsquo;ll complete the book the
following week).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Neil DeGrasse Tyson, &lt;a href=&#34;https://aipavilion.github.io/docs/tyson.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Science&amp;rsquo;s Endless Golden Age&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tim Urban (&amp;ldquo;Wait but why&amp;rdquo;), &lt;a href=&#34;https://waitbutwhy.com/2015/01/artificial-intelligence-revolution-1.html&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The AI Revolution: The Road to Superintelligence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Part I). (Posted in 2015)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;(optional) John Maynard Keynes, &lt;a href=&#34;https://aipavilion.github.io/docs/keynes.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Economic Possibilities for our Grandchildren&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, 1930.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read carefully, different from previous weeks:&lt;/strong&gt;
Everyone should (1) post at least one &amp;ldquo;fact check&amp;rdquo; (about any claim of
your choice in any of the readings), (2) post a response to one of the
readings (I&amp;rsquo;ve provided some promts for the &lt;em&gt;Sapiens&lt;/em&gt; chapters below,
but you can respond to any of the readings by posing and answering
your own question, and (3) post a (thoughtful and respectful) comment
on someone else&amp;rsquo;s fact check or response. (If you are the first one to
do (1) and (2), you do not need to do (3).)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://redd.it/9gq3og&#34;&gt;Week 3: Sapiens, Ch 14-17: Fact Checks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://redd.it/9gq41s&#34;&gt;Week 3: Other Readings: Fact Checks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://redd.it/9gq46t&#34;&gt;Week 3: Sapiens, Ch 14-17: Responses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://redd.it/9gq4bw&#34;&gt;Week 3: Other Readings: Responses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;response-prompts-for-sapiens-a-brief-history-of-humankind-chapters-14-17&#34;&gt;Response prompts for &lt;em&gt;Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind&lt;/em&gt;, Chapters 14-17&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Chapter 14) Question 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Harari writes,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;All modern attempts to stabilise the sociopolitical order have had no choice but to rely on either of two unscientific methods:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a. Take a scientific theory, and in opposition to common scientific
practices, declare that it is a final and absolute truth. This was the
method used by Nazis (who claimed that their racial policies were the
corollaries of biological facts) and Communists (who claimed that Marx
and Lenin had divined absolute economic truths that could never be
refuted).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b. Leave science out of it and live in accordance with a
non-scientific absolute truth. This has been the strategy of liberal
humanism, which is built on a dogmatic belief in the unique worth and
rights of human beings – a doctrine which has embarrassingly little in
common with the scientific study of Homo sapiens.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This seems like a pretty bleak choice. Is there no other option? (or
is one of these, less unpalatable than it seems in Harari&amp;rsquo;s writing?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Chapter 14) Question 2:&lt;/strong&gt; Harari writes about Bacon&amp;rsquo;s argument in
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.earlymoderntexts.com/assets/pdfs/bacon1620.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Novum Organum
Scientiarum&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
that &amp;ldquo;knowledge is power&amp;rdquo;. In founding the University, Jefferson
wrote,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;[T]his last establishment [a state university] will probably
be within a mile of Charlottesville, and four from Monticello, if the
system should be adopted at all by our legislature who meet within a
week from this time. my hopes however are kept in check by the
ordinary character of our state legislatures, the members of which do
not generally possess information enough to percieve the important
truths, that knowlege is power, that knowlege is safety, and that
knowlege is happiness.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(when the &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.virginia.edu/content/university-virginia-publicly-launches-3-billion-campaign&#34;&gt;University uses this
quote&lt;/a&gt;
they tend to leave out the context that it was part of a dig against
the state legislators).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much of an influence on Jefferson was Bacon? (This isn&amp;rsquo;t really a
response question, but something you might be interested in looking
into.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Chapter 16) Question 3:&lt;/strong&gt; Harari quotes Adam Smith, &amp;ldquo;In the new
capitalist creed, the first and most sacred commandment is: ‘The
profits of production must be reinvested in increasing production.’&amp;rdquo;
In Smith&amp;rsquo;s time, businesses produced physical goods, and producing
more of them required investment in capital. Today, most businesses
mostly produce virtual goods, that can be produced in unlimited
quantities without any production cost. Has this changed the
capitalist creed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Chapter 16) Question 4:&lt;/strong&gt; Harari writes, &amp;ldquo;Much like the Agricultural
Revolution, so too the growth of the modern economy might turn out to
be a colossal fraud.  The human species and the global economy may
well keep growing, but many more individuals may live in hunger and
want.&amp;rdquo; He offers two answers to this (there&amp;rsquo;s no alternative, and we
just need more patience), neither of which seems very satisfying. Is
there a better answer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Chapter 17) Question 5:&lt;/strong&gt; Discuss this quote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The history of ethics is a sad tale of wonderful ideals that nobody
can live up to. Most Christians did not imitate Christ, most Buddhists
failed to follow Buddha, and most Confucians would have caused
Confucius a temper tantrum.  In contrast, most people today
successfully live up to the capitalist-consumerist ideal. The new
ethic promises paradise on condition that the rich remain greedy and
spend their time making more money, and that the masses give free rein
to their cravings and passions – and buy more and more. This is the
first religion in history whose followers actually do what they are
asked to do. How, though, do we know that we’ll really get paradise in
return? We’ve seen it on television.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: Technology and Tyranny</title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/week2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div class=&#34;printing&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aipavilion.github.io/docs/week2.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF for Printing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://xkcd.com/1338/&#34;&gt;XKCD Land Mammals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
OurWorldInData: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ourworldindata.org/grapher/child-mortality&#34;&gt;Child Mortality&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ourworldindata.org/democracy&#34;&gt;Democracy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;assignment&#34;&gt;Assignment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the next class (Monday, 17 September), you should read:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Part Three of Yuval Noah Harari, &lt;em&gt;Sapiens: A Brief History of
Humankind&lt;/em&gt;. Everyone should read Chapters 9, 10, and 13; Chapters 11
and 12 are &amp;ldquo;optional&amp;rdquo; - I think they provide a lot of eye-opening
insights, but it is not necessary to read them for the seminar. As a
warning, Chapter 12 is about religion and is quite dismissive of
major religions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alan Turing, &lt;a href=&#34;https://aipavilion.github.io/docs/turing.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Computing Machinery and
Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (1950).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two are optional (you are not expected to read them, but I think
they are worthwhile and you&amp;rsquo;ll find them interesting):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claude Shannon, &lt;a href=&#34;https://aipavilion.github.io/docs/shannon.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Programming a Computer for Playing Chess&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Silver et al., &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1712.01815.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mastering Chess and Shogi by Self-Play with a General Reinforcement Learning Algorithm&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, 2017.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone should post at least one &amp;ldquo;fact check&amp;rdquo; (about any claim of
your choice in either the Sapiens or the Turing reading; if it is the
same as another student&amp;rsquo;s, you should provide more evidence or
counter-evidence responding to their post), and for both of the
readings write a response to at least one of the questions below or
post a free response to your own question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As discussed today, I won&amp;rsquo;t set a specific deadline for posting
responses, but everyone is strongly encouraged to not wait until the
day before class to start posting, and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to see some
constructive on-line discussion.  It isn&amp;rsquo;t necessary to finish the
readings before posting, and I would encourage reading the relevant
response prompts below as you read each reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please post your responses as comments for the appropriate post (and
you are encouraged to comment on others&amp;rsquo; responses).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://redd.it/9et27c&#34;&gt;Week 2: Sapiens, Ch 9-13: Fact Checks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://redd.it/9et2a7&#34;&gt;Week 2: Turing: Fact Checks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://redd.it/9et2h0&#34;&gt;Week 2: Sapiens, Ch 9-13: Responses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://redd.it/9et2jy&#34;&gt;Week 2: Turing: Responses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;response-questions-for-sapiens-a-brief-history-of-humankind-part-three&#34;&gt;Response questions For &lt;em&gt;Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind&lt;/em&gt;, Part Three&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose any one (or more) of these questions to respond to, or make up
your own question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 9:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Question 1: Harari writes about the unification of human cultures to the point
  where nearly all humans are closely interconnected. What is the most
  different culture you&amp;rsquo;ve experienced? How fundamentally different is
  it from your own?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 10:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Question 2: Harari writes, &amp;ldquo;We accept the dollar in payment, because we trust
in God and the US secretary of the treasury.&amp;ldquo;. What are we actually
trusting the US secretary of the treasury to do?  (Hint: since 2003,
we&amp;rsquo;re also putting a lot of trust in a different cabinet secretary.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 11:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Question 3: &amp;ldquo;As the twenty-first century unfolds, nationalism is fast losing
ground. More and more people believe that all of humankind is the
legitimate source of political authority, rather than the members of a
particular nationality, and that safeguarding human rights and
protecting the interests of the entire human species should be the
guiding light of politics.&amp;rdquo; As we discussed a bit in class Monday, in
the last few years since this was written, a lot has happened to
contradict this view, and there has been a rise of nationalism in many
countries (including, of course, the US and Britain). Is there still
reason to believe in the longstanding trends away from nationalism?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 12:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Question 4: Harari describes &lt;em&gt;Humanism&lt;/em&gt; as &amp;ldquo;a belief that Homo sapiens has a
unique and sacred nature, which is fundamentally different from the
nature of all other animals and of all other phenomena. Humanists
believe that the unique nature of Homo sapiens is the most important
thing in the world, and it determines the meaning of everything that
happens in the universe. The supreme good is the good of Homo
sapiens. The rest of the world and all other beings exist solely for
the benefit of this species.&amp;rdquo;  According to Wikipedia, &amp;ldquo;Humanism is a
philosophical and ethical stance that emphasizes the value and agency
of human beings, individually and collectively, and generally prefers
critical thinking and evidence (rationalism and empiricism) over
acceptance of dogma or superstition.&amp;rdquo; Can these definitions be
reconciled? How well does Harari&amp;rsquo;s argument hold up with Wikipedia&amp;rsquo;s
definition?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 13:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Question 5: &amp;ldquo;In memetics, &amp;ldquo;Successful cultures are those that excel in
reproducing their memes, irrespective of the costs and benefits to
their human hosts.&amp;rdquo;  Is there a better way to measure success of a
culture?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;turing-computing-machinery-and-intelligence&#34;&gt;Turing, &lt;em&gt;Computing Machinery and Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose any one (or more) of these questions to respond to, or make up
your own question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Turing sets up the game where the computer plays the role of one of
the respondents. How would things be different if the computer player
the role of the questioner (so the test was being able to classify A/B
as well as a human questioner can)?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Turing wrote this 68 years ago: &amp;ldquo;I believe that in a-bout fifty
years&amp;rsquo; time it will be possible to programme computers, with a
storage capacity of about 10^9, to make them play the imitation game
so well that an average interrogator will not have more than 70 per
cent. chance of making the right identification after five minutes of
questioning.  The original question, &amp;lsquo;Can machines think ? &amp;rsquo; I
believe to be too meaningless to deserve discussion. Nevertheless I
believe that at the end of the century the use of words and general
educated opinion will have altered so much that one will be able to
speak of machines thinking without expecting to be contradicted. I
believe further that no useful purpose is served by concealing these
beliefs.&amp;rdquo; How good was his prediction?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Turing discusses nine potential objections to his Imitation Game
test. Which one do you find most convincing (that is, where Turing&amp;rsquo;s
counter-argument is not convincing)? Or, what other objection do you
have?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Introduction</title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/week1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div class=&#34;printing&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aipavilion.github.io/docs/week1.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF for Printing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7Pq-S557XQU&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Humans Need Not Apply&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by CPG Grey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://speakerdeck.com/evansuva/class1-reduced&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;assignment&#34;&gt;Assignment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the next class (Monday, 10 September), you should read:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first two parts (Chapters 1-8) of Yuval Noah Harari, &lt;em&gt;Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yuval Noah Harari. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theatlantic.com/amp/article/568330/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why Technology Favors Tyranny&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
The Atlantic, October 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with the readings, you should:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep track of how long you spend:&lt;/strong&gt; I want to make the reading
assignments reasonable time expectation. This is a fairly long one,
since we want to make progress in the book, and our first class is
nearly a week into the semester.  In general, I would advocate for
reading less more deeply and thoughtfully, than reading too much too
quickly. So, if the volume of reading expected in this class is too
much for you to read thoughtfully, please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check facts:&lt;/strong&gt; As part of your reading, you should select at
least one claim in the readings to fact check. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve selected
the claim you want to fact check, post it as a comment to the post in
the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/aipavilion/&#34;&gt;class sub-reddit&lt;/a&gt;. A good
fact check will include references to other sources that either
support or contradict the claims in the book.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reponses:&lt;/strong&gt; for each of the readings, either (1) write a short
response to at least two of the questions below, or (2) write a
detailed response to one of the questions below, or (3) pose your own
question and provide a respone. Post it in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://redd.it/9cobz2&#34;&gt;class
sub-reddit&lt;/a&gt;. You may select any one of the
options above, but should be prepared to contribute to discussions in
the next class on many of these topics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three posts in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/aipavilion/&#34;&gt;class sub-reddit&lt;/a&gt; for your responses:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://redd.it/9cppyt&#34;&gt;Week 1: Fact Checks&lt;/a&gt; - for fact checking the claims in the readings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://redd.it/9cpqcj&#34;&gt;Week 1: Sapiens, Ch 1-8 Responses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://redd.it/9cpqk3&#34;&gt;Week 1: Responses to &amp;ldquo;Why Technology Favors Tyranny&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please post your responses as comments for the appropriate post (and
you are encouraged to comment on others&amp;rsquo; responses).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Response questions For &lt;em&gt;Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind&lt;/em&gt; (see
above - you do not need to write responses to all of these!):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sapiens&lt;/em&gt; divides history into three main revolutions: cognitive revolution (70,000 years ago), agricultural revoluation (12,000 years ago), and scientific revolution (500 years ago). Describe a different way of dividing human history, and make a case for why it is better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chapter 2 writes about millions of individuals working together to make a nuclear warhead.  Pick a simple artifact you use every day and estimate how many humans cooperated to produce it?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chapter 4: How should understanding of the historical impact of humans on other species guide our current attitudes and policies (for example, regarding endangered species and habitat protection)?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chapter 5: Why has no noteworthy plant or animal been domesticated in the past 2,000 years?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chapter 5: Harari writes, &amp;ldquo;We did not domesticate wheat. It domesticated us.&amp;rdquo; Is this true? How does it change your world view? Will future historians look at what smart phones did to your generation, and conclude they were a trap like wheat was to our predecessors?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chapter 5: &amp;ldquo;This discrepancy between evolutionary success and individual suffering is
perhaps the most important lesson we can draw from the Agricultural Revolution.&amp;rdquo; How should we measure the success of a species?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chapter 6: Harari transforms Jefferson&amp;rsquo;s introduction to the Declaration of Independence into &amp;ldquo;We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men evolved differently, that they are born with certain mutable characteristics, and that among these are life and the pursuit of pleasure.&amp;rdquo;  Can you do better?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chapter 6: Describe the imagined order(s) that most influenced your life in high school or here at UVA.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chapter 6: Discuss: &amp;ldquo;There is no way out of the imagined order. When we break down our prison walls and run towards freedom, we are in fact running into the more spacious
exercise yard of a bigger prison.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chapter 7: The three main limits of human memory presented are limited capacity, dies with the human, and only adapted to store particular types of information. Are these the most important limitations of human memory? (See Joshua Foer&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Moonwalking-with-Einstein/dp/B004QFAEJC/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moonwalking with Einstein&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on human memory training and competition.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chapter 7: &amp;ldquo;Our computers have trouble understanding how Homo sapiens
talks, feels and dreams. So we are teaching Homo sapiens to talk, feel
and dream in the language of numbers, which can be understood by
computers.&amp;rdquo; Really?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chapter 8: Harari writes about vicious circles that perpetuate imagined hierarchies of discrimination and subjugation. How can such vicious circles be ended? In human history, what are successful examples of ending them?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chapter 8 presents three theories for nearly universal male dominance in human societies, but admits that none of them are convincing. Any better theories?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Response questions for &lt;em&gt;Why Technology Favors Tyranny&lt;/em&gt; (see above - you do not need to write responses to all of these!):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Fears of machines pushing people out of the job market are, of course, nothing new, and in the past such fears proved to be unfounded. But artificial intelligence is different from the old machines. In the past, machines competed with humans mainly in manual skills. Now they are beginning to compete with us in cognitive skills. And we don’t know of any third kind of skill—beyond the manual and the cognitive—in which humans will always have an edge.&amp;rdquo; Are there any candidates for a &amp;ldquo;third kind of skill&amp;rdquo; where humans would have a permanent advantage?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;AI is a tool and a weapon unlike any other that human beings have developed; it will almost certainly allow the already powerful to consolidate their power further.&amp;rdquo; Some tools have empowered individuals; others have empowered centralized authorities. Why is AI a tool for consolidating power (or is it)?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is surprising to me that Harari&amp;rsquo;s essay does not mention China. Does what has happened in the last few decades in China contradict or support Harari&amp;rsquo;s claim that, &amp;ldquo;The decentralized approach to decision making that is characteristic of liberalism—in both politics and economics—has allowed liberal democracies to outcompete other states, and to deliver rising affluence to their people.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What kinds of human decision-making should be left to machines?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you agree with Harari&amp;rsquo;s call to action: &amp;ldquo;If you find these prospects alarming—if you dislike the idea of living in a digital dictatorship or some similarly degraded form of society—then the most important contribution you can make is to find ways to prevent too much data from being concentrated in too few hands, and also find ways to keep distributed data processing more efficient than centralized data processing. These will not be easy tasks. But achieving them may be the best safeguard of democracy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;contributing-to-the-class-forum&#34;&gt;Contributing to the Class Forum&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Post links to interesting and relevant (this is very broadly defined) articles you find, along with a short comment about why you found it interesting or whether you agree with it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Post follow-up questions (and answers)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;quote&#34;&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the website for the Pavilion Seminar, &amp;ldquo;How will Artificial
Intelligence change Humanity?&amp;ldquo;.  The seminar will be offered in Fall
2018, led by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans&#34;&gt;David
Evans&lt;/a&gt;.  Enrollment is by permission only, and strictly limited to
15 students (according to the Pavilion seminar rules).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>