<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>aiPav</title>
    <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on aiPav</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aipavilion.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Conclusion</title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/papers/</guid>
      <description>The seminar has concluded — thanks to everyone for their contributions!
You can see the Schedule and Final Paper from the seminar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Papers</title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/papers/</guid>
      <description>Lauren Austin, Aging Populations and The Effects on Society [PDF]
Emily Bishop, Artificial Intelligence Companions for the Young and Lonely
Jacob Dean, Self-Driving Vehicles, the Advance of Artificial Intelligence, and the Future of Work [PDF]
Erich Froese, Artificial Intelligence in the United States Military: Exploring Lethal Autonomous Weapons [PDF]
Megan Greatorex, Was Face ID the Right Move for Apple&amp;rsquo;s New iPhone? [PDF]
Nathaniel Grevatt, Google&amp;rsquo;s Duplex and Deception through Power and Dignity [PDF]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 12: Fairness</title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/week12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/week12/</guid>
      <description>Follow-up Here are a few links to follow-up from the today&amp;rsquo;s discussions:
  Rohit asked about the Harvard admissions lawsuit. There are two expert reports from the case: Peter Arcidiacono&amp;rsquo;s (for &amp;ldquo;Students for Fair Admissions&amp;rdquo;) and David Card&amp;rsquo;s (for Harvard). They are both long reads, and with some parts redacted, mostly about Harvard&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Dean&amp;rsquo;s List&amp;rdquo; for taking care of high donors. Unfortunately (or prehaps responsibly), the raw data for the analysis is not publicly available, but there is a lot of information in the reports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 11: Fairness</title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/week11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/week11/</guid>
      <description>Reading/Viewing Assignment Next week, we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about algorithmic fairness.
There are lots of very interesting writings on this, but I want to keep the required reading over Thanksgiving break to a minimum.
For the required reading, you can select one of these two options:
  Watch Christopher Moore&amp;rsquo;s talk, Data, Algorithms, Justice, and Fairness (Ulam Lecture at Santa Fe Institute, Oct 2018). (You can skip the excellent but long introduction by starting at 12:19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Updates</title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/paper-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/paper-updates/</guid>
      <description>Paper updates are due next week Tuesday, November 20. For everyone, you should send an email with subject line [AI Pavillion] Paper Update: &amp;lt;your title&amp;gt;. What is expected in the update depends on whether you are continuing with your first paper topic for the final paper, or you are starting a new topic.
For students starting new topics for the final paper, you should:
  In the email body, answer (1) brief statement of your topic, (2) purpose of your paper, and (3) your plans for what to do through the final deadline (this can include specific sources you will be looking into, and what you are planning to do for the final paper).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 10: Security</title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/week10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/week10/</guid>
      <description>Reading Assignment Next week, we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about security and malicious uses of AI.
There are two readings. If you did the discussion post for last week, you should select either one of these two readings; if not, you should read both of them (you&amp;rsquo;ll get a confirmation email from me if you are in this group).
  Daniel Geer. A Rubicon. Hoover Institution, Aegis Paper No 1801. February 2018. [Discussion]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 9: Papers Workshop</title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/week9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/week9/</guid>
      <description>Announcements Anton Korinek in Economics is offering a course in the Spring on Artificial Intelligence and the Future of Work&amp;hellip;and of Humanity, with lots of themes related to this seminar. A tentative syllabus is posted here.
Next week, Allison Pugh, Professor of Sociology at UVA, will visit us. You should read the paper distributed in class today, Of Seeing and Being Seen: What Humans Do for Each Other.
I will finish reading your papers by my office hours Thursday (9-10:30am).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 8: AI Control Problem</title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/week8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/week8/</guid>
      <description>Schedule Updates Office Hours this week: I will not be able to hold my Thursday morning office hours this week, but will be available later in the day Thursday. I should be around most of the afternoon, so feel free to drop by, or email me to arrange a time.
Paper 1 is due Thursday, 1 November at 4:59pm. (This is a strict deadline since I need to print the papers before leaving on a trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 7: Black Mirror</title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/week7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/week7/</guid>
      <description>Assignment for this week Mainly, you should focus on developing your papers this week, so the reading assignment is short but covers many interesting topics for class discussion. Before class on Oct 29, you should read:
  Chapter 9: The Control Problem from Nick Bostrom&amp;rsquo;s Superintelligence.
  Barack Obama, Neural Nets, Self-Driving Cars, and the Future of the World, Wired Magazine, November 2016. (Read at least up to the quote below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 6: Quadrants of Optimism</title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/week6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/week6/</guid>
      <description>Paper Draft Your First Paper Drafts are due tomorrow (Wednesday). Please submit your paper first drafts by sending an email with a PDF file attached to me, with a subject line [AI Pavilion] &amp;lt;your paper title&amp;gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll send a quick ack message so you know I received it. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to post your paper draft publicly (on the class reddit) unless you want to, but are welcome do to so also if you want to share it with the class/world at this stage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5: Papers and Purpose</title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/week5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/week5/</guid>
      <description>Talk this Friday John C. Havens will be speaking on Friday (Oct 5), 10-11:30am on Humanities, Cultures and Ethics in the Era of AI, Wilson Hall 301. He is executive director of the IEEE project on Ethics of Autonomous and Intelligent Systems.
Use this link to RSVP (there is also a lunch following the talk).
Interesting Law California passed a law about bots impersonating humans: Senate Bill No. 1001: Bots: disclosure</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4: Hoverboards</title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/week4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/week4/</guid>
      <description>Paper Ideas The idea for your first paper is due Sunday, 30 September. From the syllabus, the first paper can &amp;ldquo;focus on one aspect of how artificial intelligence has already impacted society, describing the impact of technological advances on a social, political, economic, or psychological aspect of human existence.&amp;rdquo; It is not required that your paper idea is on this topic though — anything that is relevant to the seminar theme (broadly interpreted), interesting, and with a scope suitable for a 4-5 week effort is reasonable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3: Money and Thinking</title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/week3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/week3/</guid>
      <description>Links Loebner Prize (Turing Test)
Let&amp;rsquo;s chat with Mitsuku!
The transcripts you read were from Can machines think? A report on Turing test experiments at the Royal Society, Kevin Warwick and Huma Shah, Journal of Experimental &amp;amp; Theoretical Artificial Intelligence, 2016.
Upcoming: First Paper The idea for your first paper is due Sunday, 30 September. From the syllabus, the first paper can &amp;ldquo;focus on one aspect of how artificial intelligence has already impacted society, describing the impact of technological advances on a social, political, economic, or psychological aspect of human existence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: Technology and Tyranny</title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/week2/</guid>
      <description>Links XKCD Land Mammals
OurWorldInData: Child Mortality, Democracy
Assignment Before the next class (Monday, 17 September), you should read:
  Part Three of Yuval Noah Harari, Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind. Everyone should read Chapters 9, 10, and 13; Chapters 11 and 12 are &amp;ldquo;optional&amp;rdquo; - I think they provide a lot of eye-opening insights, but it is not necessary to read them for the seminar. As a warning, Chapter 12 is about religion and is quite dismissive of major religions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Introduction</title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/week1/</guid>
      <description>Links Video: Humans Need Not Apply by CPG Grey
Slides
Assignment Before the next class (Monday, 10 September), you should read:
  The first two parts (Chapters 1-8) of Yuval Noah Harari, Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind.
  Yuval Noah Harari. Why Technology Favors Tyranny. The Atlantic, October 2018.
  Along with the readings, you should:
  Keep track of how long you spend: I want to make the reading assignments reasonable time expectation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>PAVS 4500 (004): How will Artificial Intelligence change Humanity?
University of Virginia, Fall 2018
Meetings: Mondays, 3:30-6:00PM in Rice 536.
Coordinator: David Evans (evans@virginia.edu). My office is Rice 507.
Office Hours: I will have office hours on Thursdays, 9:00-10:30am. To schedule another time, please use https://davidevans.youcanbook.me/. When my door is open, you are welcome to stop by anytime.
Course Website: https://aipavilion.github.io
Forum: We will use the subreddit, /r/aipavilion, for discussions and sharing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the website for the Pavilion Seminar, &amp;ldquo;How will Artificial Intelligence change Humanity?&amp;rdquo;. The seminar will be offered in Fall 2018, led by David Evans. Enrollment is by permission only, and strictly limited to 15 students (according to the Pavilion seminar rules).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/readings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/readings/</guid>
      <description>Readings The main books we will read for the first part of the class will be:
  Yuval Noah Harari, Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind. February 2015 (first published in Hebrew in 2011) [Amazon] [Barnes &amp;amp; Noble] [President Obama&amp;rsquo;s recommentation]
  Nick Bostrom, Superintelligence: Paths, Dangers, Strategies. 2014. [Amazon] [Barnes &amp;amp; Noble]
  The focus books for the second half of the class will be selected based on students&#39; interests and the discussions we have in class, but the most likely books include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://aipavilion.github.io/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aipavilion.github.io/schedule/</guid>
      <description>Schedule </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
